

Toronto, ON (905) 226-3345 harpreetsi9h@gmail.com Portfolio - Website

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An aspiring Java Developer with around **5 years** of experience in java/software development practices such as coding, testing, code reviews, code comments, etc. A result oriented Java Developer looking for challenging career where I can implement my coding knowledge & further enhance my skills.

## **SKILLS**

- Writing efficient, Maintainable, reusable Code with Solid understanding of object-oriented programming principles
- Strong knowledge of Languages: Java, Kotlin, J2EE, JavaScript.
- Problem-solving and Proficient in design, Debugging with attention to detail. Experience working in AGILE Methodology and collaborate in team environment by implementing Sprint & Scrum.
- Excellent verbal and written
   Communication, Team leadership and teamwork skills
- Experienced in: Native Android
   Development, Android SDK, XML,
   Jetpack, Compose, Android
   architecture components, MVVM,
   MVC, RxJava, Git, Bitbucket,
   Android Studio.
- Knowledge of: C/C++, HTML, CSS,
   React, Dart, Flutter, TypeScript,
   Wordpress, NodeJs.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Java Developer**

Infoya | Oakville, ON

October 2022 - June 2023

• Worked on **Home Depot** website cart back-end team by using **Java API Development**, **Spring & Spring Boot** technologies to develop web applications for client-server environments and worked on **Microservices** to add functionalities, **Google Cloud Platform (GCP)** for analysis & application deployment, and code improvements to existing applications. Worked in **AGILE Methodology**.

# **Android Developer**

June 2021 - February 2022

Korechi Innovations | Oshawa, ON

- Worked on a Mobile app using **Java & Android Studio** to manage and operate vehicle robots and their functionalities with **Custom Views** & Designs to fulfill requirements and used **ROS Java** to communicate with robot units locally
- Implemented MVVM design pattern for **testability** and **reusability** of code and Implemented **WebRTC** to show the **video feed** from unit **cameras** with Integrated **Google Drive** to upload & download **files**

## **Android Developer**

November 2018 - December 2019

D4D Software Pvt. Ltd | Mohali, Punjab, India

- Worked on a Health app for doctors & patients to manage & book appointments for surgeries and provide feedback for services rendered with **Kotlin** Language and implemented **Android components** & **Clean artchitecture** design pattern and **Camera & Video Recording** features using **Android Studio**. Used **Gradle** for build project.
- Worked on an E-Commerce app using Java that engages customers in businesses with Dependency Injection (Dagger2) and RESTful APIs for the app data
- Worked on different projects using **Jetpack**, **Navigation framework**, **Kotlin Flows**, **Coroutines**, **View components**.

#### **Android Developer**

October 2016 - October 2018

DevelopTech IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd | Mohali, Punjab, India

- Worked on an E-Commerce app using Java that provides guidance for plants growth & enrichment with Realm
   Database and used Canvas to Draw Custom Views with Kotlin and MVP implementation
- Worked on vocal social networking application with Social Network Integration and used Voice Filters to Recorded Voice
- Worked on Health app which made a bridge between diagnostic labs and their customers with **Socket Programming** to implement **chat service** with users and Implemented **Payment Gateway** Integrations also **RxJava** and **Retrofit** to access **REST APIs** with other **third-party libraries**.
- Worked on laundry & dry-cleaning services app with **Material Guidelines** to improve App UI and Implemented **Payment Gateway** and **Third-Party UI** Libraries to provide better
- Worked on different projects using **ButterKnife**, **AutoValue**, **SQLite**, **Crashlytics**, **Data binding etc**.

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

MovieInfo - Android app

It is an demonstration of E-Commerce Movie ordering app for Android. Used Android native MVVM design pattern, Kotlin language, View Binding, Custom views.

## FoodCo - Java BackEnd Spring Boot application

December

July 2023

It is an Food online food ordering appplication demonstration. Used **H2 Databse, Spring** 

2023

Web, Microservies and MVC design pattern with SAGA & event driven (CQRS)

artchitecture.

#### **EDUCATION**

Post-graduation diploma - Web Design & Development

April 2021

Conestoga College, Kitchener, ON

GPA: 3.59 with Academic Award: Distinction

Bachelor of Technology - Information Technology (IT)

May 2016

AGC, Amritsar, Punjab IN

## LANGUAGE

EnglishHindiPunjabiFluentFluentNative